<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="hello">Hello World, PhillyMagicGardensActivity!</string>
    <string name="hello_quote">“Art should not be segregated in museums; it needs to live free among us.”</string>
    <string name="app_name">Philly Magic Gardens App</string>
    
    <!-- Strings for the Visitor Info page -->
    <string name="contact_header">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="contact_address">Philadelphia\'s Magic Gardens\n1020 South Street\nPhiladelphia, PA 19147\nBetween 10th and 11th Streets on South Street</string>
    <string name="contact_phone">215–733–0390</string>
    <string name="contact_email">info@phillymagicgardens.org</string>
    <string name="contact_website">www.phillymagicgardens.org</string>
    <string name="hours_header">Hours</string>
    <string name="hours_summer_header">Summer Public Hours (April-October)*</string>
    <string name="hours_summer">Sunday - Thursday: 11:00 AM - 6:00 PM\nFriday and Saturday: 11:00 AM - 8:00 PM</string>
    <string name="hours_winter_header">Winter Public Hours (November-March)*</string>
    <string name="hours_winter">Sunday - Thursday: 11:00 AM - 5:00 PM\nFriday and Saturday: 11:00 AM - 8:00 PM</string>
    <string name="hours_holiday_header">Holiday Hours</string>
    <string name="hours_holiday">New Years Day: NOON - 5:00 PM\nThanksgiving: CLOSED\nChristmas Eve: CLOSED\nChristmas Day: CLOSED\nNew Years Eve: 11:00 AM - 5:00 PM</string>
    <string name="hours_note">*We often host special events or private rentals, so please visit our Updated Calendar for changes to our normal hours. </string>
    <string name="admission_header">Admission</string>
    <string name="admission_ga_header">General Admission Self-Guided Tour</string>
    <string name="admission_ga_rates">$5 for adults\n$2 for ages 6–12\nFREE for children 5 and under</string>
    <string name="admission_ga_info">Explore the fully–mosaicked gallery spaces and labyrinth sculpture garden at your own leisure. Visitors can spend as little as 20 minutes or stay for hours, viewing the thousands of diverse tiles, intricate sculptures, and varied texts embedded in the walls. Garden Guide interpreters are available to give brief introductions to Philadelphia\'s Magic Gardens and answer questions.\n*Self-Guided Tour groups over 20 people* must reserve in advance by emailing khealy@phillymagicgardens.org or by calling 215–733–0390. </string>
    <string name="admission_tours_header">Guided Weekend Tours</string>
    <string name="admission_tours_neigh">Guided Weekend Tours</string>
    <string name="admission_tours_neigh_info">(April - October)\n(includes admission to PMG)\nAdults $10\nYouth $6</string>
    <string name="admission_tours_site">Guided Site Tour</string>
    <string name="admission_tours_site_info">(November - March)\nAdults $8\nYouth $5</string>
    <string name="admission_tours_info">Weekend public tours are held Saturdays at noon and 4:00 PM and Sundays at 4:00 PM. To make reservations for a tour please call 215–733–0390. Information of our private group tour options can be found in the Education section of our website.</string>
    <string name="policy_header">Policies</string>
    <string name="policy_info">• Running and horseplay are not permitted\n• Children under the age of 16 must be under adult supervision at all times\n• Food and drink is permitted in the Magic Gardens\n• Casual photography is permitted and encouraged during our regular hours and events.  Professional photographers and filmmakers must contact us in advance.</string>
    <string name="parking_header">Parking</string>
    <string name="parking_info">Metered and two-hour parking in the immediate vicinity is available along South and Bainbridge Streets, and along numbered streets. Free untimed parking is available on streets farther south. </string>
    <string name="accessibility_header">Accessibility</string>
    <string name="accessibility_info">Much of the main indoor gallery at Philadelphia\'s Magic Gardens and parts of the outdoor sculpture garden are accessible to people in wheelchairs. Both the basement and the sculpture garden have stairways and narrow passageways that are not equipped with ramps, elevators, or railings. Visitors with disabilities are encouraged to further explore the work of Isaiah Zagar through tours that lead visitors through PMG and down the sidewalks and alleys of the surrounding neighborhood. Please contact us and we will try to accommodate your needs.</string>
    
    <!-- Strings for the POI pages -->
    <string name="poi_index_header">Points of Interest</string>
    <string-array name="poi_object">
        <item>Introduction</item>
        <item>Aerial Photograph by Gabe Kirchheimer</item>
        <item>Clarence Schmidt Lettered Tiles</item>
        <item>Nek Chand and Ferdinand Cheval Lettered Tiles</item>
        <item>Gate</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="poi_info">
        <item >Philadelphia\'s Magic Gardens (PMG) is a mosaicked visionary art environment, gallery, and community arts center that preserves, interprets, and provides access to Isaiah Zagar\'s unique mosaic art environment and his public murals. The Magic Gardens site, Zagar\'s largest artwork, includes a fully tiled indoor space and a massive outdoor mosaic sculpture garden that spans half a block on Philadelphia\'s famous South Street. Inside, visitors can view folk art statues, bicycle wheels, colorful glass bottles, Zagar\'s hand-made tiles, and thousands of glittering mirrors. The installation pays tribute to Zagar\'s artistic influences, along with community and personal experiences.\nOpen to visitors daily, PMG has become a unique Philadelphia destination, hosting year-round, low-cost public programs within its own distinctive venue and the surrounding community. PMG, a nonprofit organization, inspires creativity and community engagement by educating the public about folk, mosaic, and visionary art. </item>
    	<item>Philadelphia’s Magic Gardens is a 3,000 square foot mosaicked building and labyrinth created by artist Isaiah Zagar over 14 years.  Zagar originally purchased 1020 South Street in 1994 as an artist studio space but began to clean up and mosaic the trash-strewn abandoned lots next door to his property. In 2002, the owner of the lots decided to sell them and threatened to have the mosaicked labyrinth bulldozed at Zagar’s expense. The community recognized the site as a unique part of Philadelphia and united to form a non-profit organization, newly entitled Philadelphia’s Magic Gardens, to purchase the lots and save the visionary art environment from demolition.</item>
    	<item>Clarence Schmidt was one of Isaiah Zagar’s earliest and most important influences. When Zagar was 19, he visited Schmidt’s <i>My Mirrored Hope</i>, a visionary art environment in Woodstock, New York. The experience of walking through Clarence’s labyrinth of wood, windows, found objects, and aluminum foil-covered trees was overwhelming to the young artist. Zagar befriended Schmidt and realized he wanted to make art that embodied the same full sensory experience as <i>My Mirrored Hope</i>.  Schmidt passed away in 1978, decades after his environments burned to the ground from electrical accidents.  </item>
    	<item>Zagar frequently references other visionary environments and artists from around the world. It is important to Zagar that people know that there are other artists who have the same impulse to transform large spaces into elaborately-decorated, full sensory experiences. His work features the names of artists like Helen Martins from South Africa, Nek Chand Saini from India, Joseph Ferdinand Cheval from France, and Simon Rodia from Los Angeles. He also pays tribute to influential artists that have greater public recognition for their achievements, such as Pablo Picasso, Marcel DuChamp, and Vincent Van Gogh.</item>
    	<item>Isaiah Zagar and his wife Julia worked in the Peace Corps in Peru for three years in the 1960s. After relocating to Philadelphia in 1968, they opened the Eye’s Gallery on 4th and South Streets, showcasing folk art that they purchased in South America. This was the first site Zagar ever mosaicked. During the late 60s and 70s, South Street was transforming from an abandoned street to a thriving cultural destination due to the efforts of newly-settled artists and activists.  This period became known as the “South Street Renaissance.”  The Eye’s Gallery is still open today and continues to sell folk art from Latin America and around the world. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="poi_location">
    	<item></item>
    	<item>Lobby</item>
    	<item>Gallery One, South Wall</item>
    	<item>Outdoor Labyrinth, First Alley Walls</item>
    	<item>Courtyard North</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="poi_theme">
    	<item></item>
    	<item>The Non-Profit</item>
    	<item>Clarence Schmidt</item>
    	<item>Visionary Environments &amp; Their Creators</item>
    	<item>Eyes Gallery </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="poi_photo">
    	<item></item>
    	<item>Aerial photograph by Gabe Kirchheimer</item>
    	<item>Clarence Schmidt Lettered Tiles embedded on PMG Gallery One Wall</item>
    	<item>Nek Chand and Simon Rodia Lettered Tiles</item>
    	<item>Gate</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <!-- Button Labels -->
    <string name="pmg_logo_desc">PMG main logo</string>
    <string name="pmg_splash_desc">Splash image for the app introduction</string>
    <string name="map_button_text">Garden Map</string>
    <string name="info_button_text">Visitor Information!</string>
    <string name="menu_button_text">Menu</string>
    <string name="poi_index_button_text">Points of Interest</string>

</resources>